franklintempleton.com 2005-12-18

# Privacy Policy

|  |  |   
| Privacy Policy  
---  
  
We respect your privacy and value the trust you place in us when you share your personal information with us. The way we may use your personal information is discussed in our official privacy notice. Having said that, we know you might have some additional questions about privacy on the Web.   
  
First, we'll talk about privacy as it relates to using this website. Then, we'll cover the broader privacy issues concerning a mutual fund shareholder's relationship with our company as a whole. If you want to skip the Web-related privacy issues, you can jump ahead and read our official Mutual Fund Privacy Notice.   
  
Web-Related Privacy Issues   
  
How we use information provided on the Web   
  
Your email address. We collect your email address when you register for account access. If we need to contact you about transactions or account activity on the site, your email address lets us do that quickly. If you sign up for electronic delivery of documents, we'll need your email address for that, too. Both of these services require that you maintain an updated email address with us.   
  
Even if you're not registered for account access, we may need to ask for your email address. For instance, if you ask for a referral to a financial advisor or subscribe to our email newsletter, we'll need your email address to respond to your requests.   
  
We won't send emails you haven't asked for unless there's a good reason. If you don't want to receive these emails, use the opt-out link at the bottom of the email.   
  
Survey information. Occasionally we may ask you to participate in a brief survey to help us make smart choices as we look for ways to improve the site. If you choose to participate, information you provide won't be identified with you personally.   
  
Personal data entered in calculators. When you use calculators and planning tools on the site, you may need to enter information such as your age or even certain dollar amounts like how much you save each month.   
  
We don't collect or store this kind of information. It's only used to perform the calculation you're asking for. 

Our Mutual Fund Privacy Notice   
  
Your Privacy Is Our Priority   
  
Franklin Templeton Investments is committed to safeguarding information provided to us by individual shareholders of our U.S.-based Franklin, Templeton and Mutual Series Funds. This notice is designed to provide you with a summary of the non-public personal information we may collect and maintain about current or former investors; our policy regarding the use of that information; and the measures we take to safeguard the information. The Franklin, Templeton and Mutual Series Funds, Franklin Templeton Distributors, Inc., and Franklin Templeton Bank & Trust ("FTB&T"), trustee for retirement plans, (together referred to as "we," "our," and "us" throughout this notice) do not sell non-public personal information to anyone and only share it as described in this notice.   
  
Information We Collect   
  
When you invest in our Franklin, Templeton and Mutual Series Funds or establish a retirement plan with FTB&T as trustee, you provide us with your non-public personal information. We collect and use this information to service your accounts and respond to your requests. The non-public personal information we collect falls into the following categories: 

  * Information we receive from you on applications or other forms, whether we receive the form in writing or electronically. For example, this information includes your name, address, tax identification number, birth date, investment selection, beneficiary information, and possibly your personal bank account information and/or email address if you are signing up for certain account options.
  * Information about your transactions and account history with us, or with other companies that are part of Franklin Templeton Investments, including transactions you request on our website. This category also includes your communications to us concerning your investments.
  * Other general information that we may obtain about you such as demographic information. 

Disclosure Policy   
  
To better service your accounts and process transactions or services you've requested, we may share non-public personal information with other Franklin Templeton Investments' companies. From time to time we may also send you information about products/services offered by other Franklin Templeton Investments' companies although we will not share your non-public personal information with these companies without first offering you the opportunity to prevent that sharing. 

We will only share non-public personal information with outside parties in the limited circumstances permitted by law. For example, this includes situations where we need to share information with companies who work on our behalf to service or maintain your account or process transactions you've requested, when the disclosure is to a party representing you, or when required by law (for example, in response to legal process). Additionally, we will ensure that any outside companies assisting us in marketing our products and services, or with whom we have joint marketing agreements, are under contractual obligations to protect the confidentiality of your information, and to use it only to provide the services we've asked them to perform.   
  
Confidentiality and Security   
  
Our employees are required to follow procedures with respect to maintaining the confidentiality of our investors' non-public personal information. Additionally, we maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect the information. This includes performing ongoing evaluations of our systems containing investor information and making changes when appropriate.   
  
|  |   
---
